Artyom Makarov

Business Partnering Assistant



Personal Info

Address

34 Optikov St

Saint-Petersburg 197082

Russia

Phone

+7 960 248 87 50

E-mail

makarovartyom.ma@gmail.com

Date of birth

1995-12-19

Portfolio

https://makarovartyom.github.io

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/artyom-makarov-774605125

Languages

English - fluent

Russian - native

References

Andrey Naraevsky, Director Liner and Business Development at Global Container Service Ltd.

Please, see in LinkedIn recommendation section.

I have 2+ years experience in analytical and business related roles, working closely with **cross-functional stakeholders** from Finance, Commercial and Engineering sides.

Motivated by setting up and solving business problems, manipulating complex data with applying statistical and machine learning methods.

Automated 80% of **analytical/visualization** tools, contributed to imporve weekly forecasting by statistical techniques.

Education

2013-09 -2017-06 NATIONAL RESEARCH UNIVERSITY HIGHER SCHOOL OF ECONOMICS (ST. PETERSBURG)

Bachelor of Economics

Financial Markets and Institutions

Certificates

2019 Machine Learning Specialization - University of Washington, MOOC

2018 Math in Python for Data Analysis - Moscow Institute of Physics and

Technology, MOOC

Experience

2017-04 - **Business Partnering Assistant**

2018-11 MAERSK LINE, LLC

1. Working closely with commercial team and engineering, <u>manipulate SQL data and Teradata</u>, creating <u>custom connectors to Microsoft products</u>, embedding Azure services.

2. Weekly <u>forecast improvement</u> for biggest ocean corridor - working on time series, implemented

SARIMA + Linear models for top commodities weekly demand.

- 3. <u>Automated targeting</u> for commercial department customers profit segmentation, applied in Python.
- 4. Produced new Power BI <u>dashboards</u>, gathering <u>business insight</u> for top management.

2016-07 - Intern, Finance

2017-04 *METSO, LLC*

- 1. Customers business results analysis, financial statement modelling.
- 2. <u>Data mining</u> and <u>manipulation</u> with on-premises software.

Hard skills

Python (pandas, scikit-learn, matplotlib, BeautifulSoup)

SQL (data manipulation (MS SQL/MySQL), work with SQLite Python module and Google BigQ

Machine learning algorithms implementation for Regression, Time series, Classification and Clustering problems

Data visualization - Power BI, Plotly/Dash: interactive dashboarding, presentations

Soft skills

Partnering both with **commercial** and **engineering sides**, business requirements follow up.

Sharing insight within the team, **project thinking** (experience of BI tools development inside partners' team).